Dylan Barnard

dylan.barnard@gmail.com dylankb.github.io github.com/dylankb linkedin.com/in/dylankb

Collaborative and detail-oriented software engineer with ~2 years experience working with React, Rails, and Ember, including Ember's core team. Previous experience as a product manager. Co-creator of Layr, an experimental, decentralized cloud file storage service.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer | Freelance, San Francisco, CA

Sept. 2017 - Present

Contributed to projects ranging from a JavaScript chatbot demo to a user notifications system in Rails

Software Development Intern | Home Depot Quote Center, Vancouver, WA

June 2017 - Sept. 2017

- Launched first mobile web version of e-commerce site used by 50K employees as part of a 4-person team using React/Redux and SCSS
- Promotion to a permanent Software Developer position offered August 2017

Engineering Intern | Tilde, Inc., Portland, OR

Oct. 2016 - Mar 2017

- Paired to build a new version of Tilde's admin site by creating a new Rails API and Ember. is front-end
- Met high code quality standards to contribute 100+ pull requests to Skylight APM and other codebases

Contract Web Developer & Business Analyst | ICE Cable Systems, Portland, OR

Feb. 2016 - July 2016

Wrote well-tested Rails code to improve functionality of e-commerce site and internal analytics tools

Data Product Manager | Smart Agriculture Analytics, Beijing, China

Oct. 2014 – Sept. 2015

Managed both technical development and content research to launch company's first data product

PROJECTS

Layr: Decentralized cloud file storage system for private and secure storage on a P2P network in Node.js.

- Collaborated with two other developers to implement remote data audits across a network, efficient file shard distribution, and a smart-contract based payment system for incentivizing participation.
- Read more about the project at https://layr-team.github.io/layr-project/

Trello-Bone: KanBan app with CRUD operations on cards, lists, plus drag-n-drop. Node.js & Backbone.js

Project links at http://dylankb.github.io/projects/#trello-bone

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Strong: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript (ES5/ES6), React, HTML/CSS, SQL (Postgres)

Knowledgeable: Redux, Node.js, Express.js, Ember.js, SCSS, Backbone.js, decentralized systems

TALKS

Introduction to Decentralized (P2P) Applications: SFNode - July 12, 2018 — http://y2u.be/8sN3cT5T-5g

EDUCATION

Launch School, An Online School for Software Engineers, 2016

Lewis & Clark College, B.A, International Affairs & Foreign Languages (Mandarin & Spanish), 2010

OTHER SKILLS & AWARDS

Chinese language proficiency: Passed HSK Level 6, China's highest level language proficiency test